紙牌屋
前情提要
翻譯   杏仁斯嘉麗
翻譯   肉松
翻譯   國士章魚X
翻譯   蘇小黛
翻譯   草草
翻譯   沫沫
時間軸   Kallen
時間軸   念念
后期   餓得慌
顧問   老杜
校對   草草
總監   草草
紙牌屋
人人影視傾情奉獻
第五季  第十集
弗蘭西斯·安德伍德就職典禮
"易援"女士
輸入安全語句讀取文件  區分大小寫和空格媽媽把備用鑰匙放在哪(四個詞  無大寫)我最喜歡的棒球運動員(全名)你在奧斯丁的酒店房間留了什么(一個詞)
總統想當你的朋友
The president would like to be a friend to you,
但你讓他很難做
but you're making it very difficult.
我就想看弗蘭西斯·安德伍德當著我的面
I want to be there when Francis Underwood says to me
宣布提高醫保水平
that there will be an increase in Medicare.
只要他一句話  我就是他鐵哥們
He does that, I'm his friend.
所以我要致力于改善醫保政策
That is why I am committed to fixing Medicare
取得成效前  我不會增加一毛錢預算
before I devote one more dime to the program.
他想找幫我們獲勝的人的麻煩
He's going after the people who got us here.
我要煽動共和黨人
I'm encouraging the Republicans
重啟宣戰委員會
to restart the Declaration of War Committee,
調查總統
to investigate the president.
羅梅洛想換護衛  道格
Romero's trying to change the guard, Doug.
而我們就是護衛
And we are the guard.
-道格  -部長女士
- Doug. - Madam Secretary.
他昨天是第三位
He was number three yesterday.
這個安東尼·莫雷蒂再過幾小時就要死了
This man, Anthony Moretti, he's just hours away from dying.
那就讓他死
Then let him die.
我正坐在這里跟你說話
I am sitting right here talking to you.
不是雷米·丹頓或杰姬·夏普
Not Remy Danton or Jackie Sharp.
克萊爾知道了
Claire knows.
沃克公開聲明了
Walker went on record.
告訴他是我發動本黨議員彈劾他
Told him I was the one who whipped the votes for impeachment.
只要我們站出來  他就完了
You and I go on the record, he's done.
不可能在大選之前
There's no way subpoenas get them
傳召他們去委員會作證了
in front of the committee before the election.
有傳言說委員會
There's a rumor the committee's
想和加勒特·沃克做交易
trying to make a deal with Garrett Walker.
真相要曝光了
The truth is coming out.
一起來揭露吧
Be part of the truth.
我爺爺說  死人不瞑目
The dead sleep with their eyes open, my grandfather would say.
他們從過去注視著你
They're watching you from the past...
杰姬·夏普
Jackie Sharp.
羅梅洛一刻都沒浪費
Romero wasted no time.
你有什么用
What good are you?
你們民主黨人真是驚喜不斷
You Democrats are full of surprises.
她的律師不讓我們靠近她
Her lawyers won't let us get anywhere near her.
因為他們在商量她的證詞
Because they're negotiating her testimony.
我們到底是怎么到這一步的
How the hell did we get here?
羅梅洛知道消息  黨內有人給他通風報信
Romero was privy to information. Someone from within the party.
他威脅要追究她拉票
He's threatening to go after her for whipping votes
來換取雷米·丹頓先生的競選經費一事
in exchange for campaign funds from a Mr. Remy Danton,
令人"震驚"的是她和雷米上過床
who, shockingly, she was sleeping with.
她不會因為一段婚外情就作證
Well, she's not testifying because of an affair.
她作證是因為她不想進監獄
She's testifying 'cause she doesn't want to go to jail.
任何人出庭作證都只因為這個
Which is the only reason anyone testifies.
道格  盯住委員會里剩下的民主黨人
Doug, keep at the rest of the Democrats on that committee.
確保他們守規矩
Make sure they stay in line.
我會在我黨這邊發力  但  羅梅洛
I'll keep working my side of the aisle, but... uh, Romero.
他是個混蛋
He's a prick.
一個依然想當黨鞭的混蛋
Mmm-hmm, prick who still wants whip.
泰瑞·烏麥克一直忠心耿耿
Terry Womack has been very loyal.
是啊  忠誠和厲害是兩碼事
Yeah, well, there's loyal, and then there's good.
烏麥克給了你什么
What has Womack brought you?
宣戰委員會是他解決的嗎
Did he kill the Declaration of War Committee?
11月時他幫你拿下密蘇里了嗎
Did he deliver Missouri for you in November?
夠了
That's enough.
滿足他吧
Let's give it to him.
有時你得做出艱難抉擇
Look, sometimes you have to make hard choices.
我會跟泰瑞談的
I'll talk to Terry.
羅梅洛得給他找個地方落腳
Romero's gonna have to find a place for him to land, and...
落在哪我是在意的
where that is matters to me.
就這樣吧
That'll be all for now.
好  先生
Yes, sir.
我會讓道爾去查
I'm gonna put Doyle on this.
我們已經審查過羅梅洛了
We already vetted Romero.
不  我是說查厄舍
No, I mean on Usher.
尸體保存得非常完好
The body is remarkably well-preserved,
除了手腳  因為都凍傷了
except for the extremities, which frostbite took care of.
但牙齒是完好的
But dental is intact.
我們在南極的同行正在全力配合
Our counterparts in Antarctica are cooperating fully,
12小時內尸體會到我們手上
and the body will be in our possession within the next 12 hours.
報關后我會派人把它運回來
I'll have it in transit after customs.
我們希望尸體在運輸中失蹤
We'd like the body to get lost in transit.
女士
Ma'am?
它必須失蹤
It needs to get lost.
好
Yes.
好  謝謝  助理局長格林
Okay. Thank you, Assistant Director Green.
我們再聯系
Uh, keep in touch.
-我還以為你已經睡了  -還不能睡
- I thought you'd gone to bed. - Can't yet.
-那是誰  -我們不認識
- Who's that? - No one we know.
湯姆  我說了  我們不認識
Tom, I said it's no one we know.
你聽說過他們在意大利阿爾卑斯山發現的
You ever hear about the 5,000-year-old man they found
冰凍五千年的干尸嗎
frozen in the Italian Alps?
沒有
No.
他的頭骨后面被砸出了坑
His skull was caved in... from the back.
他大概根本沒料到
He probably never saw it coming.
被痛打一頓  留下等死
Beaten and left for dead.
留下等死是一個古老的概念
Left for dead is an ancient concept.
當人被凍死的時候
You know, when you freeze to death...
最后會感覺非常熱
the last thing you feel is extreme heat.
疼
That hurts.
抱歉
Sorry.
我剛看到了弗蘭西斯
I saw Francis out there.
他好像很焦躁
He seems on edge.
能怪他嗎
Can you blame him?
好點了嗎
Better?
最重的罪是入店行竊
Shoplifting is the worst of it.
近來幾次在街上買毒品  而被法庭強制戒毒
A couple of recent street buys that led to court-mandated rehab.
她就在那里生活  工作  買毒品
That's where she lives, where she works, where she scores...
但依我看就是個二十多的女人  努力想活到三十
But all I see here is a woman in her 20s, trying to get to 30.
-她是個威脅  -我不懂
- She's a concern. - I don't get it.
嘉文·奧爾西去委內瑞拉之前  她和他有聯系
She was in touch with Gavin Orsay before he left for Venezuela.
-道格  -納森
- Doug... - Nathan!
你的語氣有點急  我們可能得討論下
There's a bite to your tone that we might need to discuss.
她是個隱患  是個癮君子
She's a loose end and an addict.
這兩樣合在一起很糟
That's a bad combination.
重新裝修了
It's a clean slate.
唐納德·布萊斯的品味對我來說太暗了
Donald Blythe's taste was a bit too dark for me,
所以我全拆掉了
so I stripped it all back.
我選了一副畫  還在路上
I have chosen one painting so far that's on its way, though.
撒德·彼得森的尸體處理好了
Thad Peterson's body is taken care of.
他叫無名氏
His name is John Doe.
他化成灰我都認識
I'd recognize him anywhere.
這本來會傷害到我國的
This would've been very embarrassing to some interests
一些重要利益
that are important to this country.
我也不希望他的家人看到他這樣
And I wouldn't want the family to see him this way.
約旦大使館有什么消息
What's the news from the Jordanian Embassy?
艾丹·麥卡倫仍不愿
Aidan Macallan still won't
透露他跟佩特洛夫說了什么  沒說什么
reveal what he did or didn't tell Petrov.
總統希望他立刻從避難地
Well, the president wants him brought back from his asylum
回到美國
to the United States immediately.
我們應該耐心點兒
I think we should give it a little more time.
我在想讓你插手明不明智
You know, I wonder if it was such a good idea to bring you in on this.
-你承諾了  -我知道  艾哈邁迪...
- You promised-- - I know. Ahmadi...
我們派了特種部隊去當地追蹤
We've got Special Forces on the ground, tracking.
俄羅斯在敘利亞的存在
Russia's presence in Syria
讓此事比我曾經想得要復雜
is making this more difficult than I once thought.
我得知道麥卡倫跟佩特羅夫說了什么
I need to know what Macallan told Petrov.
男人制造爛攤子的天賦
It never ceases to astonish me
總能讓我吃驚
how talented men are at making a mess.
打擊同黨對你來說可沒好處
Uh, it's not gonna serve you to go after your own party.
你從不放棄
You never stop.
杰姬·夏普不會作證的
Jackie Sharp will never testify.
那她就得進監獄
Well, then she'll go to jail.
艾力克斯  你證明不了他們之間有交換條件
You can't prove it, Alex. You can't prove the quid pro quo.
她好像覺得我可以
She seems to think I can.
如果你換種方式
If you play it a little differently,
還有機會實現目標
you have a chance to get what you want.
我們可以給你黨鞭的位子
We're offering you whip.
-我不想要了  -什么
- I don't want it anymore. - What?
天啊
Jesus Christ.
那就財政委員會
Ways and Means, then.
在下次黨代會上做主講
The keynote at the next convention.
我只想讓弗蘭西斯·安德伍德進監獄
What I want is for Francis Underwood to go to jail.
天吶  這對你有什么好處
My God. How is that gonna help you?
真的  這對你有什么好處
Really? How's it gonna help you?
還有別的辦法做到
There's another way to go at it.
你想揚名
Wanna make a name for yourself?
你想讓總統生不如死
You wanna make the president's life a living hell?
那就慢慢來
Draw it out.
讓委員會繼續  但要溫水煮青蛙
Keep the committee going but at a slow burn.
你不是為他工作嗎
Aren't you working for him?
政府成員  一次找一個人
Members of the administration, you bring 'em in one at a time.
你可以糾纏幾年  一邊穩住自己的地位
You could ride this for a couple of years and secure your place.
而你壓制住總統
While you keep the president in check.
別傳喚杰姬·夏普  否則計劃會胎死腹中
Don't end it before it's begun by calling Jackie Sharp.
你知道我看好你
You know I see good things for you.
讓我為你規劃接下來的八年
Let me plan out your next eight years.
與你合作的候選人
The candidates you worked with...
他們中有多少人反復等待
how many of them have waited and waited
誤了時機
and lost their moment?
嗯  沒錯
Yeah, that's right.
我分析當下時局  現在屬于我
I'm reading the moment, and this is mine.
讓我在第三街下車
Let me out on Third Street.
我送你到雷伯恩大樓
I'll drop you at Rayburn.
不  我總是走最后46米
No, I always walk the final 50 yards.
可能有機會做政治交際
Never know when you might get a chance to press some flesh.
是啊
Yeah.
你好  我是艾力克斯·羅梅洛
Hi, I'm Alex Romero.
我代表亞利桑那州第七區
I represent the Seventh District of Arizona.
我想知道你昨晚失眠的原因
I want to know what keeps you up at night,
我今天好解決這一問題
so I can work all day to address it.
未來屬于我們所有人
The future belongs to all of us.
但愿我能得到你的支持
I hope I can count on your support.
你覺得怎么樣  馬克
What do you think, Mark?
你可是專家
I mean, you're the expert.
就這兒
Right here.
羅梅洛拒絕了  一般的條件他也不感興趣
Romero said no, and the usual offers don't interest him.
他感興趣  你只是恨自己感興趣
Oh, he's interested. He just hates himself for it.
關于委員會的共和黨人  我有了進展
I am making headway with the Republicans on the committee.
他們都有不可告人的過去  大多有目擊證人
They all have pasts, most of them have witnesses.
無論如何  杰姬·夏普不會作證
One way or another, Jackie Sharp won't be testifying.
那你為什么這么難搞定
So why are you having so much trouble
這位年輕議員
with this one young congressman?
他很固執
He's tenacious.
他讓我想起了你
He reminds me of you.
我根本看不出來  我們再聯系
Well, I don't see that at all. We'll talk later.
我可以聯系丹頓
I could reach out to Danton--
我們曝光他  他就會曝光我們
We expose him, he'll expose us.
那你有什么建議
Well, then what do you suggest?
繼續做總統該做的事
That I go on being presidential.
我只有這一個辦法
That's the only way that I can deal with this.
我的就職頭百天啊
It's my first 100 days, for God's sake.
弗蘭西斯
Francis...
我們會捉住艾哈邁迪的
we're going to get our hands on Ahmadi.
世界上再多的艾哈邁迪
There aren't enough Ahmadis in the world.
也抵不掉我們做的那些事
Not for all we've done.
那怎么辦
Then what?
比如毀了羅梅洛  這件事總能辦到吧
Destroy Romero, for one. Can we at least take care of that?
然后毀誰  整個民主黨嗎
And then who? The rest of the Democratic Party?
我知道我在做什么  克萊爾  我當過總統
I know what I'm doing, Claire. I've been president before.
我也當過
So have I.
給我接泰瑞·烏麥克
Get me Terry Womack.
你作為副總統的職責是給我建議
Your job as vice president is to advise.
做決定是我的職責
My job is to make the decisions.
泰瑞  沒錯  我就是問問情況
Terry, yes, I'm just checking in.
我希望你知道我們都支持你
Well, I want you to know that we support you.
那混蛋還想當黨鞭  做夢去吧
That bastard asked for whip, but that's never gonna happen.
只要我在臺上就別想  我把話給你撂這兒
Not while I'm in this office. I wanted to assure you.
我一向在能出力的地方幫忙
I've always tried to help where I can.
你在衛生和人類服務部幫不上忙嗎
And you couldn't help at Health and Human Services?
我們這里做了很多了不起的事
The agency does some amazing work.
你接受采訪時曾說那是你夢寐以求的工作
Well, you were quoted as, uh, calling your position a dream job.
人是可以有多個夢想的
It's possible to have more than one dream.
我可以讓助手帶你逛逛
I can have my assistant give you a tour.
給你看看海地發來的視頻
Uh, show you some of the video from Haiti
拍的是過去幾個月  我們在那邊的
and some of the work that we've been doing there
工作和成績
over the last several months.
我一定會把
I will be sure to include
你們組織寫進我的報道
your organization in the piece I'm writing.
-我相信你們的事業  -謝謝
- I believe in the work you're doing here. - Thank you.
和安德伍德政府合作  感覺怎么樣
What was it like, uh, working with the Underwood administration?
他們還行  且這么說吧
They were fine. Let's leave it at that.
我采訪過許多非常棒的組織
You know, I've met with, uh, many wonderful organizations so far.
-弗州兒童守衛基金  -他們的工作很棒
- The Virginia Children's Defense Fund. - They do some great work.
塔伯特聯盟
The Talbot League?
這個組織也很棒
Another terrific group.
還有安東尼·莫雷蒂紀念基金
The Anthony Moretti Memorial Fund.
他們我倒沒什么了解
I don't know anything about them.
他們是器官移植宣傳組織
Organ transplantation awareness.
是嗎
Oh, is that right?
非常抱歉
I'm so sorry.
太失禮了  但我又太餓了
It's rude, but I was famished.
謝謝你肯來見我  我給你拿菜單
Thank you for meeting me. Let me get you a menu.
謝謝不用了  我隨后還有午餐會
Uh, no, thank you. I have a lunch right after this.
那就好  一定要有個吃午飯的地方
Good. You should always have one on the books.
-戴維斯女士  -你擔心艾丹
- Miss Davis? - You're worried about Aidan.
你稱呼他有什么昵稱嗎
Do you call him anything for short?
為什么問我這個
Why would you ask me that?
我不知道總統或者副總統
I don't know if the president, or vice president,
告沒告訴你  但麥卡挺好的
has informed you, but Mac is fine.
問題在于他知道什么
It's what he knows is the problem,
他都跟誰說過
and who he may have told it to.
他只想活下去
He wants to stay alive.
沒錯
Yes.
但這種人才得小心
But those are the ones you have to watch out for.
我上次和艾丹說完話他就上了出租車
Last I spoke to Aidan was minutes before he got in a cab.
我不知道他有什么  也不知道他做了什么
I don't know what he has or what he's done.
我只是奉命行事
I only do what I'm told.
我就在胡佛大樓上班
I'm in the Hoover Building.
那真是全城最丑的一棟樓
It's the ugliest building in... in the city.
我每次進去都閉著眼
I close my eyes as I walk in.
有空來坐坐  尤其是你想找人談談的時候
Stop by any time. Especially if you're in the mood to talk.
像你這樣口風緊的人  我們用得上
We could use someone who says as little as you do.
麗薩
Lisa!
-我一直在找她  -我不知道她在哪
- I've been looking for her. - I have no idea where she is.
-我幫你拿吧  -不用了
- Let me help you with that. - No. No, I'm okay.
-我很樂意幫你拿  -你嚇到我了
- I'm happy to carry it for you. - You're scaring me.
我只是擔心她而已
I'm just worried about her. That's all.
我戒了
I'm clean.
很好
Good.
至少我努力在戒  求你別纏著我了
At least I'm trying to get clean. Please leave me alone.
就是
Just...
如果你有瑞秋的消息  請你
If you hear from Rachel, just, uh...
告訴她我全都打點好了
tell her I've taken care of everything.
她可以回來了  不會有事的
She can come home and everything will be fine.
我想她  你知道嗎
I miss her, you know?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
你不接嗎
You going to answer that?
我說得對嗎
So, was I right?
你的電話響了
Your phone is ringing.
你按邊上的按鈕就可以直接掛斷
You know, you can just hang it up by pressing the button on the side.
-你不用拒接  -我習慣了
- You don't have to decline-- - I'm a creature of habit.
是的  你是對的
So, yeah, you were right.
這部電話只用過一次  撥打了一個號碼
This phone has only been used once to call one number, once.
我用了生產序列號
I mean, I used the manufacturer's serial number
追蹤到了它的經銷商所在地
and tracked down where it's distributed to.
是在  杜邦環島的一家商店
It was a, um... A shop in Dupont Circle.
打給了誰
And who did it call?
查無此人
Comes up unknown.
不過前幾位數字
But the prefix...
聽著  你得找警察或聯調局談
And, look, you're gonna have to talk to the police or the FBI.
-我不能一直  -別擔心  我擔著
- I just can't keep-- - Don't worry. It's on me.
那個號碼的前幾位  我看著像政府號碼
The prefix on the call, it looks like a government number to me.
喂
Hello.
他跟蹤你了  什么時候
He followed you? When?
-我得去  -好的
- I've got to... - Yeah.
好的  如果你覺得現在待的地方安全
Okay. Okay, if you feel safe where you are,
那就待著  我來找你
stay there. I'm coming to you.
有什么不能在電話上告訴我的
So what couldn't you tell me over the phone?
杰姬·夏普
Jackie Sharp.
她怎么了
What about her?
你真不知道嗎
You really don't know?
我還以為這事是白宮傳出來的
I thought this was coming out of the White House.
馬上要爆出來了
The story's about to break
說她拿立法換取競選資金
that she traded legislation for campaign funds.
消息來源呢
The source?
所以是未經確認的
So, unconfirmed.
一小時內就會上《德拉吉報道》了
It's going to be on Drudge within the hour.
你真沒什么要說的嗎
You really don't have anything to say?
如果是真的  很遺憾看到民主黨
If it's true, it's just sad to see the unexpected fall
一顆曾經的新星這樣出人意料地隕落
of a once rising star in the Democratic Party.
得了吧
Stop it.
夏普本能讓委員會拿下一分
Sharp would've been a get for the committee.
如果你仍愿意作證  我們就仍愿意談
If you're still willing to appear, we're still willing to talk.
回見
See ya.
我們這個政府不是這么辦事的
This is not how we do things in this administration.
你希望她不作證
You wanted her not to testify.
現在羅梅洛不可能逼她就范了
And there's no way Romero can force her to now.
你讓我的新聞發言人
You've put my press secretary
和他的人處于了非常尷尬的境地
and his staff in a very difficult situation.
有人泄密  并不是你
It was a leak, and it didn't come from you.
我真心覺得這樣才能占得先機
I really felt this was the way to get ahead of it.
這叫占得先機
This is getting ahead of it?
我向你們保證  她的律師
I guarantee you her lawyers
現在一定讓她保持沉默  緘口不談
tell her to plead the Fifth now, across the board.
最重要的是  對涉及你們的事閉嘴
Most importantly, where it concerns you.
但這都是在我跟佩特羅夫談判時發生的
But all of this happened while I was negotiating with Petrov.
對大眾而言  你當時是第一夫人
Oh, to the public, you were the First Lady,
正不眠不休地守在丈夫的床邊
sitting vigil by your husband's bed.
所以這都是在唐納德·布萊斯的監管下發生的
So, actually, all of this happened under Donald Blythe's watch.
如果你們覺得我越界了  很抱歉
I'm sorry if you think I overstepped.
我是想保護你們
I was trying to protect you.
他做了正確的事
He did the right thing.
我不介意他做了什么
Oh, I don't mind what he did.
我介意的是他做事的方式
I mind the way he did it.
-莉安  -副總統女士
- LeAnn... - Madam Vice President.
抱歉  我的行程太滿了
I'm sorry my schedule is so full.
沒關系  我非常理解
No, I completely understand,
畢竟你要處理那么多事
with everything that you're dealing with.
抱歉我這么固執
I'm sorry for being so insistent,
但我覺得應該讓你知道
but I thought you should
簡·戴維斯昨天來找我了
know that Jane Davis came after me yesterday.
找你
Came after you?
她想讓我去為她工作  不知你是否知情
She wanted me to work for her. I didn't know if you knew.
為她做哪方面的工作
In what capacity?
這點我還不確定  不過
That, I'm not clear on, but it...
她想要關于艾丹·麥卡倫的信息
She wanted information about Aidan Macallan.
希望你知道我絕不會透漏一個字
I hope you know I would never say a word.
謝謝你讓我知道這些
Thank you for bringing this to my attention.
女士  我希望能討論一下我的前途
Ma'am, I was hoping we could discuss my future.
莉安  我很樂意討論你的前途  但現在不行
Oh, LeAnn, I would love to discuss your future, but not yet.
如果你愿意  女士  艾丹的事我能幫忙
If you would like, ma'am, I can help with Aidan.
你盡管吩咐
Anything that's required.
很高興知道你有這個心
That's good to know.
你覺得莉安·哈維不會告訴我嗎
Did you think LeAnn Harvey wouldn't tell me?
我從不假設人們會做什么或不會做什么
I never assume what people will do or won't do.
-我以為我們在默契合作  -沒錯啊
- I thought we were working well together. - We are.
繞過我套取信息
Well, going around me to get information
只會在你我之間造成嫌隙
will only create discord between us.
我并不想這樣  克萊爾
I wouldn't want that, Claire.
-戴維斯女士  -總統先生
- Miss Davis. - Mr. President.
抱歉我來晚了
I'm sorry I'm late.
副總統告訴我你的聯系人
The vice president has told me that your contacts
再次跟丟了艾哈邁迪
have once again lost track of Ahmadi.
是  我解釋過
Yes, as I explained,
敘利亞局勢每天都在天翻地覆
Syria is like a different country one day to the next.
這你得歸咎于維克多·佩特羅夫
Yes, well, you can thank Viktor Petrov for that.
我是怪他
Oh, I do.
夫人
Ma'am?
我得失陪了  簡
Oh, you'll have to excuse me, Jane.
我現在都快忙瘋了
The schedule is crazy these days.
當然
Oh, of course.
有沒有搞錯  國務院加國防部
Really? The State Department, the Pentagon,
連個艾哈邁迪都捉不住
we can't get close to Ahmadi?
我只想要和平
I just want peace.
是啊  和平的利潤最豐厚
Yes, there's nothing that makes profits like peace.
而有利潤的地方最和平
And nothing makes peace like profits.
總統先生  我能有話直說[遲鈍]嗎
Mr. President, may I be blunt?
我可不覺得你是遲鈍的人  戴維斯女士
Well, I would never accuse you of dullness, Miss Davis.
霍姆斯城將會遭受一場毒氣襲擊
There's going to be a gas attack happening in the city of Homs.
而如果說  您劃下紅線
If you were to, let us say, draw a line in the sand...
然后又發生了這樣慘烈的襲擊
and if this tragic attack were to happen...
那美國政府將不得不
the US government would have
加派三萬多名士兵進駐
to send in an additional 30,000 or so soldiers.
以保護石油管線
To protect the oil lines,
阻止佩特羅夫拿下大馬士革
to keep Petrov from getting into Damascus.
當然了  還要保護人民
And, of course, to protect the people.
這么大規模的軍隊幾乎就是全面占領了
That's venturing close to occupation with those kind of numbers.
我只是在說  也許宣戰委員會
All I'm saying is maybe the Declaration of War Committee
終于可以辯論他們該辯論的了
could finally debate what they were mandated to.
開戰
A war.
你認識馬克·厄舍嗎
Do you know Mark Usher?
認識  我們合作過
Yes, we worked together.
當時他在協助一位眾議員
He was handling a congressman.
馬克
Mark.
有人給你拿過什么嗎
Has anyone offered you anything?
沒有  不用  謝謝了
Oh, no, I'm good. Thanks.
你和簡·戴維斯合作過嗎
Have you ever worked with Jane Davis?
戴維斯是她繼父的姓
Davis is the stepfather's name.
一個只干了一任的參議員
A one-term senator.
總之
Uh, anyway, yeah,
她曾對我的一位客戶有點興趣
she was interested in a client I had, at some point.
國會議員候選人
A candidate for Congress.
可憐人  厄舍一意識到他不夠強硬
Poor guy. The minute Usher realized he wasn't formidable enough,
就甩手走人  讓他自生自滅了
he just dumped him. Let him go.
但馬克就這樣
But that's Mark.
他擅長發現人才
He has an eye for talent.
喜歡密切關注你  而他自己卻站得遠遠的
Likes to keep you close while he keeps himself remote.
但是他不同意她在一些問題上的立場
But he disagreed with some of her positions,
于是資金就斷掉了
the money went away.
聽我說  千萬別讓簡騙了你
Listen, don't let Jane fool you.
她看上去可能有點  沒有章法
She can seem a bit... haphazard...
但只要他利用完了你
But once he's done with you...
就會像關上開關那么干脆決絕
it's as if a switch gets turned off.
但她冷酷無情
But she is merciless.
要多專一就有多專一
Single-minded as a single mind can be.
怎么了  我今天忘了吃飯了
What? Forgot to eat today.
你給我查出什么了
What have you got for me?
-不知道  -少跟我"不知道"
- I don't know. - Don't do "I don't know."
我去見了梅瑞迪斯·李
Saw Meredith Lee.
我提到了莫雷蒂基金  器官移植
I mentioned the Moretti Fund, organ transplants, uh...
她看起來有點緊張  可是  我說不好
She got a little tense, but... I don't know.
你怎么沒告訴我你被開除了
Why didn't you tell me you were fired?
-原來是你  -就是我和你女友說了話
- Oh, that was you? - Who talked to your girlfriend? Yeah.
多久了
How long?
有什么區別  我窮途末路了
What's the difference? I'm tapped.
我們在干什么呢
What are we doing here?
我不喜歡有人在我車上吃東西
I don't like eating in my car.
我覺得勞拉·莫雷蒂的丈夫
I think Laura Moretti's husband
在捐贈名單上被插隊了
was jumped on the donor list.
-這你是從哪聽說的  -直覺
- Where the hell did you get that? - My gut.
不信我分析給你聽
I can lay it out for you.
敢這么說話  你最好說到做到
Yeah, you say something like that, you better.
沙林毒氣  主要襲擊霍姆斯近郊的平民區
Sarin gas. Mostly against civilians in suburban areas of Homs.
-我們在和一幫畜生斗  -太可怕了
- We're dealing with animals here. - It's horrifying.
你知道我過去一直在盡量克制  但是
Now, you know I've always shown restraint in the past, but...
我打算發布行政命令  部署軍事行動了
I'm going to be making an executive order for military action.
先空襲  然后地面部隊進駐
Air strikes followed by ground troops.
你得向聯合國提交報告
You'll need to present to the UN.
這個情報是哪來的
Where is this intelligence coming from?
簡報里都寫了
Well, it's all there in the briefing.
但既然我們知道這事會發生
But if we know this is going to happen,
我們為什么不提前制止呢
well, then why aren't we stopping it before it does?
弗蘭西斯還留著你的辭職信
Francis held on to your resignation letter.
他想把它撕掉
And he wants to tear it up.
我知道這幾個月來你多么艱辛
I know how difficult these past few months have been for you.
我們要求你做了很多
We've really asked a lot.
但等我們部署了軍事行動
But once we're on the other side of this military action,
我們會準許你如愿離開政府
you have our blessing to leave the administration if you choose.
但當然  我們更希望你留下
But, of course, we'd prefer if you stay on.
希望這是不言自明的
Hope that goes without saying.
對平民使用
Using weapons of mass destruction
大規模殺傷性武器是戰爭罪
against civilians is a war crime.
我很感激有機會能完成此事
I appreciate the opportunity to see this through to the end.
我們就希望你會這么說
We were hoping you would say that.
謝謝你  凱茜
Thank you, Cathy.
謝謝  總統先生
Thank you, Mr. President.
你擔心她嗎
Are you worried about her?
我們得開始想
We need to start thinking about
我們身邊的人了
the people we surround ourselves with.
這讓我想到了湯姆
Which has made me think of Tom...
他現在已經沒理由留在這里了  是吧
who doesn't really have a reason to be here anymore, does he?
沒有正式理由
Not an official one, no,
但我想或許我們可以給他個顧問之名
but I thought maybe we could bring him on as a consultant.
當然  這取決于你
Well, of course, that's entirely up to you.
只是一天的時間和精力有限
There's just only so much time and energy in a single day,
我覺得我們該不斷自省
and I think we need to constantly be asking ourselves,
"我是否盡可能明智地利用我的時間和精力了"
"Am I spending it as wisely as I can?"
-謝謝  -簡  真抱歉
- Thank you. - Jane, I'm so sorry
-從派對上把你叫走  -沒事
- to pull you away from your party. - No, no, no.
-當我在電話上聽到你的聲音  -我就是
- When I heard your voice on the phone... - I just... I just...
-我不知道該怎么辦  -出什么事了嗎
- I don't know what to do. - Did something happen?
安德伍德夫婦在計劃
The Underwoods are planning
對霍姆斯進行空襲  增派軍隊
air strikes and a troop surge in Homs.
-太可怕了  -你了解這事嗎
- How awful. - Do you know anything about this?
佩特羅夫把那里變成了地獄
Petrov is making the whole region a disaster.
沒有哪個卷入中東局勢的人能得到好處
No one who ever got tangled up in the Middle East came out ahead.
隨佩特羅夫去吧
Let Petrov own it.
有可怕的事將要發生
There's something terrible that is going to happen...
我們可以阻止
that we can prevent.
這樣啊
I see.
我要向聯合國提交我方紅線警告
I'm scheduled to present some kind of red line at the UN.
-但我們還可以退一步的  -我要怎么幫忙
- But we can still pull back. - How can I help?
跟總統和副總統談談
Talk to the president, the vice president.
我會的
I will.
他們真可怕  是吧
They're terrible, terrible people, aren't they?
簡
Jane...
對他們一定要小心
be very careful with them.
當然
Of course.
這是老友的忠告
That's from an old friend.
我們還是朋友吧
Are we still friends?
當然
Of course.
他說總統接受的肝臟
He says the liver the president received
本該是給一個叫安東尼·莫雷蒂的人的
was supposed to go to a man named Anthony Moretti.
他說道格逼迫
And he says that Doug forced
當時的衛生和人類服務部部長
then Secretary of Health and Human Services
把總統排在名單最前
to put the president at the top of the list,
結果莫雷蒂因此死了
which resulted in Moretti's death.
道格還跟他的遺孀發生了關系
Oh, and Doug also has become involved with the man's widow.
干得漂亮
That's a nice touch.
他有證據嗎
And does... does he have proof?
關于戀情嗎  這個簡單
About the relationship? It's easy to prove that.
名單的話  他知道梅瑞迪斯·李有所隱瞞
But the list, he knows that Meredith Lee is hiding something.
他打算再去找她談
And he's ready to go back and talk to her about it.
你信任他嗎
Do you trust him?
我不知道他干嗎要編造這些
I don't know why he'd make any of this up.
我在外面
Hey, I'm outside.
你玩得開心嗎
Did you have a good time?
我在這種場合已經開心不了了
I never do at those things anymore.
必要之惡
Necessary evils.
不像以前了
It's not like the old days,
你還能結識出人意料的人
when you used to meet surprising people.
是人們不那么出人意料了
Did people get less surprising
還是我們不容易被打動了
or are we less easily surprised?
是啊
Well, exactly.
-我的車來了  -她跟我問了你
- This is me. - She asked me about you.
-我猜到了  你怎么說的  -你...
- I figured. What'd you say? - That you're...
強大  什么的
formidable, etcetera.
我也這么跟他說你的  什么的
Yeah, I told him the same about you, etcetera.
他可以當個偉大的總統
He could be a great president.
但他想做嗎
But does he want to be?
而且什么算偉大
And what is great?
還有她
And then there's her.
她怎么樣
What about her?
她怎么了
如果鮑勃或泰瑞是副主席
Because if Bob or Terry were the ranking member,
我就找他們了
I'd be talking to them.
我要羅梅洛做光桿司令
I want Romero's clerk stripped.
對  他給委員會成員的任何預算
Yeah, whatever budget he's got for his seat on that committee.
不不  我這是為了黨派
No, no, I'm asking for the sake of the party.
杰姬·夏普的事我們躲過一劫  但這事沒完
Look, we survived Jackie Sharp, but it's not gonna end there.
事實上  我在因為
The truth is I'm being punished
為我們選民最在乎的事抗爭而受懲罰
for fighting for the issues that our base cares most about.
對  謝謝
Yes, and thank you.
道爾說幾乎查不到厄舍的任何料
Doyle says there's almost nothing on Usher.
他喜歡賭博  一般能贏
He likes to gamble, usually wins.
但問題是  道爾找過馬歇爾
But here's the thing... Doyle spoke with Marshall,
我們知道他離開康威團隊時并不愉快
who we know did not have a happy exit from the Conway campaign.
他說  厄舍加入我們政府前
Now, he said that before Usher joined our administration,
他還打算培養羅梅洛競選總統
he was grooming Romero for a presidential run.
先生  我認為他在兩頭討好
Sir, I believe he's playing both sides
這個委員會的目標
of whatever this committee is after.
我不是民主黨人  杰弗里
I'm not a Democrat, Jeffrey.
我還是共和黨  只是碰巧在白宮工作
I'm still a Republican, just happen to work for the White House.
我是說  趁現在還行  控制下艾力克斯
All I'm saying is let's rein Alex in while we still can.
等他把自己的黨派攪翻了天
'Cause after he rips through his own party,
就會去折騰我們黨了  不是嗎
he'll come after ours, wouldn't you think?
杰弗  你是主席
Yeah, and Jeff, you're the chair...
不  什么  不  聽我說
No... What? No, listen.
等等  等等
Wait. Wait! Wait.
你欠我的  我們都知道
And you owe me, and we both know it,
這種事我不會大聲說出來
and that's not the kind of thing I like to say out loud.
什么
What is?
什么時候的事
When did that happen?
確認了嗎
Confirmed?
嗯
Yeah?
好吧
Yes, well...
沃克要作證
just because Walker's gonna take the stand,
不代表他會說什么  是吧
doesn't mean he'll say anything. Right?
你今早對我說的那個詞是什么
What was that word you said to me this morning?
就是現在沒人用了的那個
The one no one uses anymore?
黃昏的
Crepuscular.
對了
Right.
一些我最喜歡的動物就是晨昏性的
Some of my favorite animals are crepuscular.
喂
Yes.
什么
What?
什么時候
When?
天吶  該死
Jesus! God damn it!
克萊爾
Claire!
-克萊爾  -我在廚房
- Claire! - I'm in the kitchen.
沃克要作證
Walker's gonna testify.
-什么時候  -最早下周
- When? - Early as next week.
他會說他跟漢默施密特說的那些話
He's gonna say the same thing he said to Hammerschmidt.
不會有新傷害
There's not gonna be any new damage.
-我們不能確定  -我們去找厄舍
- We don't know that for sure. - Let's get Usher.
我早上肯定要找他
You bet I'm gonna talk to him in the morning.
你去哪
Where are you going?
在這房子里找塊空蕩的地方
To get some goddamn space in this house!
我可以解決沃克  我們給他開條件
I can take care of Walker. We'll make him an offer.
讓他回到政壇
A place back on the stage,
去哪個資金雄厚的大學當校長  他會接受的
chancellor of some well-endowed university. He'll take it.
他可能會  但首先
He just might. But first,
我要知道你有羅梅洛什么料
I want to know what you have on Romero.
完全沒有
I don't have a thing.
-得了  -道格  別失禮
- Please. - Doug, let's not be rude.
這我難以相信
I find that impossible to believe.
如果我知道  你會知道的
If I did, you would know it.
你和我都是老手了
You and I have been at this a long time.
你愿考慮一個候選人都肯定先審查過他
You wouldn't even consider a candidate without vetting him first.
我覺得艾力克斯很有前途
I thought Alex had a future.
是啊  就我所知可以競選總統
Yeah, a run for the presidency as I understand it.
他像上漿的白襯衫一樣干凈
He's clean and crisp as a starched white shirt.
你得做出決定  馬克
You're gonna have to make a decision, Mark.
是為我和克萊爾工作  還是怎么
You wanna work for me and Claire, or not?
我已經聯絡了我自己黨派的人
I have already reached out to members of my own party.
我為幫助你動用了我的政治資本
I've used my political capital to help you.
但你還是沒回答我的問題
But you're still not answering my question.
我已經回答了
I think I have.
我不需要讓你或安德伍德夫人相信我的價值
And I don't need to convince you or Mrs. Underwood of my worth.
認識您很榮幸
It's an honor to meet you.
賽斯  杰弗瑞斯先生稍后會去找你
Seth, Mr. Jeffries will catch up with you momentarily.
我得長話短說了
I'm going to keep this brief.
如果你的說法是真的
If what you're saying is true...
道格·斯坦普救了我丈夫一命
Doug Stamper saved my husband's life.
是的
He did.
還因此害死了別人
And he also cost someone else his.
我猜你是那種有很多欲求的人
Well, I suspect you're the kind of man that wants many things.
但你犯了個錯誤
But you have made a mistake.
職業上講  我只有一樣一直渴求的東西
There's only one thing, professionally, that I've always wanted.
就是進白宮工作
It's to work in the White House.
賽斯會送你出去
Seth will see you out.
抱歉剛剛不得不走開
Sorry for the interruption.
你說到哪了
You were saying...
凱茜一直是個好人
Cathy was always a very good person.
她內心是的  她有良心
At her core, she has a core.
保佑她
Bless her.
霍姆斯的事對她可能太為難
This whole Homs initiative might be too difficult for her.
你讓人很難讀懂
You know... you're very hard to read.
這也合理
Which makes sense.
這幾年來  你一直左右逢源
For the last several years, you've been a familiar face.
一定很累人
Must get exhausting.
你能跟他一起歡笑的人都很少吧
Must be hardly any people you can even share a laugh with.
你該想想該怎么好好利用我
You should figure out how to take full advantage of me.
我可以幫你如愿
I can help you get what you want.
如果你告訴我你的愿望
If you tell me what it is.
我喜歡幫助他人
I enjoy helping others.
我覺得你知道我的愿望
I think you know what I want.
是啊
Yes...
但你是現在想要  還是四年后要
But do you want it now or in four years?
我要全世界看到艾哈邁迪被逮捕
I want the whole world to see Ahmadi's capture...
鋪天蓋地的報道
on every news outlet and every screen.
為了黨派利益  我更希望沃克先生不要作證
For the good of the party, I'd prefer Mr. Walker not testify.
我在考慮離開宣戰委員會
I'm considering taking myself off the Declaration of War Committee.
艾力克斯  你不用那么做
Alex, you don't have to do that.
你可以隨意怎么處置它
And you can do what you will with it.
但條件是總統要做正確的事
But that's conditional on the president doing the right thing.
是什么
And what is that?
辭職
Resigning.
再說一遍  我只是為黨派考慮
Again, I'm only thinking of the party.
嗯
Yeah...
你他媽以為你是誰啊
Who the fuck do you think you are?
-別對我說粗話  -閉上臭嘴
- Oh, don't use that language with me... - Shut the fuck up.
你根本不知道你在做什么
You have no idea, none, about what you're doing.
請你離開我的辦公室
I'd like you to leave my office.
你給我聽好
Now you listen carefully to me.
-我說  -閉嘴  艾力克斯
- I said... - Shut up, Alex!
聽聽這個頭條
Here's a headline for you.
"艾力克斯·羅梅洛勾結康威州長
"Alex Romero colluded with Governor Conway
利用宣戰委員會
to use the Declaration of War Committee
幫他贏得大選"
to help him win an election."
-沒有  -得了  你清楚你做了什么
- No. - Please, you know you did.
-看這多簡單  -滾出去
- See how easy that is? - Get out!
聽證會上只會有你一個人  我剛見過沃克
You're gonna be all alone at your hearing. I just left Walker.
他打算保持沉默  你會出丑的
He's gonna plead the Fifth. You'll look like a fool.
你想出頭  沒人介意
You want to be out front? No one has a problem with that.
他們希望你出頭  因為你也會倒得最快
They want you there, because you'll be the first to fall.
"為了黨派"
"For the good of the party."
做個好夢  議員
Sleep tight, Congressman.
-誰知道威爾的事  -暫時還沒人
- Who knows about Will? - No one, not yet.
還有呢
What else?
我現在為什么還要保護你
Why I'm still protecting you at this point...
我自己都不明白
I don't even understand myself.
沃克打算保持沉默
Walker's gonna plead the Fifth.
羅梅洛也不會折騰
And Romero won't rock the boat.
多謝了  馬克
Thank you, Mark, I appreciate that.
我建議你安排新聞發布會
I would suggest you schedule a press conference
就在聽證會之后
for right after the hearing.
好
All right.
告訴我你做過的最惡劣的事
Tell me the worst thing you've ever done.
不好選
It's hard to pick.
-我說真的  -我也是
- I'm serious. - So am I.
假裝愛一個我并不愛的人
Pretended to love someone when I didn't.
可以說  那是最糟的
In a way, that was the worst.
那人知道嗎
Did the person know?
她假裝不知道
She pretended not to know...
但她知道
but she knew.
她很難受
It was awful for her.
但我為那個錯誤付出了代價
But I paid for that mistake, too.
那種事  會傷害一個人
Those types of things, they take a toll.
真是奇妙  有些選擇毫無意義
It's strange how some choices mean nothing
也有一些會決定你的余生
and others govern the rest of your life.
我做過一些可怕的事
I've done some terrible things.
你不用告訴我
You don't have to tell me.
弗蘭西斯殺了佐伊·巴恩斯
Francis killed Zoe Barnes.
克萊爾
Claire.
弗蘭西斯殺了彼得
Francis killed Peter.
別說了
Stop.
還會再死許多人
And so many more are gonna die.
別說了
Stop.
我不怕你
You don't scare me.
你該怕
I should.
艾丹
Aidan.
我不叫艾丹了
Not anymore.
你怎么到這兒來的
How did you get here?
有扇門開了  我就出來了
A door opened, I walked out.
聽著不太對勁
That doesn't sound right.
我拿到了簽證  和今晚的機票  我只是
I got a visa and a flight tonight. I just...
我只是想最后再來看看你
I just wanted to see you one last time.
等等  誰要送你走
Wait. Who's getting you out?
無所謂了
That doesn't matter.
-你說什么了  -其實什么都沒說
- What did you say? - Honestly, nothing.
我們必須和安德伍德夫婦談談
We have to talk to the Underwoods.
-還是算了吧  -這根本說不通
- Nah, I don't think so. - This does not make sense.
你總是喜歡開好車
Well, you always liked to drive a nice car.
艾丹  跟我來吧  我來解決
Aidan, come with me. I'll fix this.
我還想讓你跟我走呢  我也給你備了條出路
You come with me. I've a way for you to get out.
那好吧
Well, all right, then.
等到明天早上再告訴別人你見到了我
Now, don't you tell anybody you saw me until the morning.
我為什么還要告訴別人我見到了你
Why would I tell anyone I saw you at all?
不是吧
Really?
等等
Wait.
-給  拿上這個  -不行
- Here, take this. - No.
拿著  至少上飛機之前要拿著  好嗎
Come on. At least until you get on the flight, all right?
我撤了
I'm out.
睡不著
Can't sleep?
外面這么冷  你該披上外套
It's freezing out here. You should have a coat on.
我喜歡
I like it.
別去見沃克
Don't meet with Walker.
我覺得這不是個好主意
I think it's a bad idea.
這會提醒他  他最好該怎么做
It'll remind him of his best course of action.
你錯了  我很抱歉  但是你錯了
You're wrong. I'm sorry, but you're wrong.
厄舍已經打點好了
Usher has it under control.
你總是想做什么就做什么
You always do what you want.
湯姆不想走
Tom doesn't want to leave.
湯姆沒資格選
Tom doesn't get to choose.
外面冷  你進去吧
It's cold. You should go in.
能麻煩你把道格·斯坦普過去三年
If you could get me Doug Stamper's addresses
住過的所有地址給我...
for the last three years...
你知道瑞秋和麗薩的照片條
And do you know what happened to the photo strip
去哪了嗎
of Rachel and Lisa?
不見了
It's gone.
我們得自己表明我們的立場
We need to lay out our positions ourselves.
我已經在去紐約的路上了
I'm already on my way to New York.
我不希望你說或者做什么
I don't want you to say or do anything
讓你感到不舒服的事
that makes you feel uncomfortable.
我不會和政府立場相左的  我不希望這樣
I won't contradict the administration. That's not my wish.
我們需要劃下紅線
We need to draw a line in the sand.
當然  我還上飛機嗎
Yes, of course. Should I get on my flight?
我覺得你最好還是調頭回來吧
I think it might be best if you turn around and come back.
聽你的
Whatever you think.
就讓沃克保持沉默吧
We'll let Walker plead the Fifth.
然后我們再碰頭協調立場
Then we'll regroup and make sure we're on the same page.
好吧  調頭回去吧
Okay. We need to head back.
"當心糾纏不清的聯盟"  總統先生
"Beware entangling alliances," Mr. President.
通常都認為這句話出自華盛頓
You know, that quote is often attributed to Washington,
但其實是杰斐遜說的
but it was actually Jefferson who said it.
總之我想先來見見你
Anyway, I wanted to catch you before,
趕在馬克和你的律師來之前
Mark and your lawyer got here.
總統先生
Mr. President.
我知道這對你并不輕松
I know this hasn't been easy for you.
其實一個人的適應能力幾乎不可限量
Well, the truth is, one can get used to almost anything.
總之  恭喜你
Well, at any rate, congratulations.
你就要擔任國內
You're about to become the chancellor
頂尖大學的校長了
of one of our finest universities.
我們為名譽付出的代價高昂
It's a high price we pay for respectability.
總之  我就是來打個招呼
Anyway, I just wanted to say hello.
并且感謝你所做的一切
And to thank you for all you're doing.
用不了多久
In not too long,
你就會和那些前總統一樣
you're going to become one of those ex-presidents
你的成就會讓大家
whose work will make everyone...
忘記過去
forget the past.
我也曾是美國總統
I was once the President of the United States.
沒錯  你的確是
Yes, you were.
然后總統之位被你偷走了  弗蘭克
You stole the presidency, Frank.
別這么說  加勒特
Now, Garrett...
都是好久以前的事了
This is ancient history,
但以現代政治的標準來看
but by modern political standards,
我是以壓倒性優勢當選的
my election was a landslide.
我原本打算改變這個國家
I was gonna change this country.
但后來  發生了一些事
But then... uh, things happen.
人們說謊
People lie...
為與他們同步你只好也撒謊
You lie to keep up.
你一直以來被稱贊的優點
The things that you've been lauded for all your life,
突然都成了致命缺陷
those are suddenly fatal flaws.
曾經和你風雨同舟的人
People who've been with you through thick and thin,
你以為永遠不會辜負你的人  還是辜負你了
who you thought would never fail you, they fail you.
你會和討厭的人結成別扭的同盟
You make strange alliances with unsavory people.
當一切清晰起來時  已經太晚
And it all becomes clear way too late.
其他任何人都不會真正明白
And no one else truly understands.
除了就任過的人
Except someone who's been in the office...
你不能指望這個職位
You can't expect the office
能放大你的能力
to do anything more than what you bring to it.
-我這么做是為黨的利益  -我知道
- I'm doing this for the party. - I know.
這令人欽佩
And it's admirable.
特莉莎怎么樣
How's Tricia?
我們挺好  雖然花了些時間
Well, it's taken time, but we are good.
孩子們也都很好
The kids are doing well.
這只是開始
Well, this is just the beginning.
今后  你我會有更多的合作
You and I are gonna be working a lot more together from now on.
真的嗎
Is that so?
道格
Doug.
湯姆  今天上午很忙
Tom, it's a busy morning.
我現在不能提供任何引述
I don't have any quotes right now.
等你有時間  我想坐下來
When you have a moment, i'd like to sit down
問你幾個關于麗薩·威廉姆斯的問題
and ask you some questions about Lisa Williams.
不好意思  你在說什么
I'm sorry. What are you talking about?
等你有時間  和我說一聲  道格
Let me know when you're free, Doug.
如果你想要一個聲明
If you'd like a statement,
賽斯·格雷森的辦公室很快會發一篇新聞稿
Seth Grayson's office will be issuing a press release shortly.
你住在杜邦環島附近  對吧
You live near Dupont Circle, don't you?
我可以正式宣稱  是的  我住那附近
I will go on the record and say yes, I do.
沃克總統
President Walker,
希瑟·鄧巴的
it's been established in
特別檢察官報告中明確稱
Heather Dunbar's special prosecutor's report
我們有理由...
that we have reason to--
議員  我已向主席
Congressman, as I mentioned to the chair
和委員會的其他成員提過
and the other distinguished members of the committee,
我建議我的委托人
I am advising my client
目前對關于他就任美國總統期間的所有問題
to plead the Fifth at this time for all questions regarding his tenure
行使第五修正案的權利
as President of the United States of America.
同為民主黨人  我得說
I must say, uh, that as a fellow Democrat,
這很不尋常
this is highly irregular.
是的  議員  的確
Yes, Congressman, yes.
但鑒于目前進行的調查...
But in light of ongoing investigations--
其實  我愿意回答議員的問題
Actually, I will answer the congressman's questions.
請提問吧
Please, ask your question.
你任總統期間
Under your administration,
有來自中國商人的數百萬美元資金
millions of dollars were illegally laundered
經非法洗錢  影響了美國大選
from Chinese businessmen to affect American elections.
是真的嗎
Is this true?
對  是真的
Yes. That's true.
你能否告訴我們
And can you tell us what, if any,
時任副總統弗蘭西斯·安德伍德
was then Vice President Francis Underwood's
在其中的參與情況  如果有的話
involvement in this scheme?
他似乎是其中一名總設計師
Well, it appeared to me, he was one of its chief architects.
你這話是什么意思  先生
And, uh, what exactly do you mean by that, sir?
那是他的主意
It was his idea.
馬克  你還是去別的地方吧
Mark, I think you need to be elsewhere right now.
我們要對此采取回避態度嗎
Are we gonna bury our heads in the sand with this?
不是  你要離開
No, you're going to leave,
副總統和我來決定怎么做
and the vice president and I are going to decide what to do.
沃克食言了  我們說好了的
Walker reneged. We had a deal.
如果需要你  我們會告訴你的
We will let you know if you are needed.
-先生  -這不是請求
- Sir... - That was not a request.
你為什么非要去和他談
Why did you have to go talk to him?
一定會有出路的  弗蘭西斯
There has to be a way out, Francis.
是嗎  有嗎
Does there? Is there?
這就是我的總統任期嗎
Or is this my presidency?
永遠是攻擊目標
Forever with a target on my back.
被糾纏  被追捕
Haunted and hunted.
莉安  如果你聽到這個  說明我死了
LeAnn, if you're hearing this, it means that I'm dead.
1958年以前  美國總統是沒有退休金的
所以杜魯門退休離開華盛頓時  生活極度窘迫
自己開著車回到老家密蘇里  買不起房子  只好去親戚家住
同年的《前總統法案》規定給退休總統發放等額于內閣部長工資的退休金
總統們的退休生活才有了基本保障
克林頓退休時正當壯年  閑不住的他成立了克林頓基金會  到處做慈善
一度成為世界上最影響力的基金會之一
但在2016年大選中  克林頓基金會的募資受到了廣泛質疑
一些人指出  許多外國政府和團體可能是因為希拉里做了國務卿才會捐款
大小布什兩父子總統  退休后基本上都選擇了不問世事的隱居生活
兩個人都回到了德州  老布什落戶休斯頓  小布什選擇了達拉斯
老布什相對更活躍一些  會出席一些公開活動
任上毀多譽少的小布什則更加低調  除了一些必須參加的活動
更多把精力放在了為非洲做慈善  以及支持老兵權益的一些活動中
為打發時間  他還開始學習繪畫  而且現在油畫作品頗有成就
2016年出版了一本畫冊  銷量非常好
剛退休不到半年的奧巴馬  花了很多時間去歐洲和加勒比海度假
隨行的都是富商名流  出入都是噴氣飛機  豪華游艇
但豪華假日只是表象  奧巴馬的手下在華盛頓租了一間辦公室
同政府的現任官員聯系緊密
現總統特朗普遭遇一連串丑聞后  其支持者指責奧巴馬
在背后暗中支持反對特朗普的政治力量
按慣例退休總統都會離開華盛頓
但奧巴馬以想保證女兒讀完高中為由  退休后在華盛頓租了一間豪宅
不久前  媒體報道他出資八百萬美元把這棟豪宅買了下來
看來短期內他是不會離開美國的政治中心了